A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, C; 34.4 cubic ft. 86 boxes
  - Office, O; 20.0 cubic ft. 50 boxes
    - Engard, W. A. - Esty, E. B. (Mrs.), 140.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 104, Reel 12, Frame 0464)
      Personal aid; Standard Oil Company press relations; Northern Pacific Railroad Company; Republican Party; Baptist Church; F. T. Gates report; New York City Mission and Tract Society; Expectation Club; Forest Hill; Gustavus Adolphus Orphan Home; bankers and brokers; real estate; Central Park horse speeding driveway; Missouri, Kansas & Texas Railway Company; United Society of Christian Endeavor; American Sunday School Union; Driving Club of New York; Epoch Publishing Company; Equitable Trust Company; New York University; United Brethren in Christ; Mariner's Temple Sunday School; Swiss Home; oil industry and shipbuilding inventions; Ladies Aid Society; "The Examiner;" Equitable Life Assurance Society Ladies Agency; Muskogee Indian Territory, Baptist mission; Latin American lumber investment; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church Ladies Sewing Circle.
    - Estwick - Eyears, 140.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 105, Reel 12, Frame 0604)
      Attorneys; painting for sale; Baptist Church; German Evangelical Church; Johnson Missionary Society; personal aid; University of Chicago; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; personal loans; Lake Erie Seminary; Connecticut Baptist Convention; Boys' Club of St. Marks Place; Vacuum Oil Company; National Bank of Commerce; Valley Railway bonds; Cleveland Club; lawsuit; real estate; New York State Canals Engineer's Department; water power of Niagara River; "The Examiner;" tailor.
    - Fabian - Fasig, S., 119.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 106, Reel 12, Frame 0744)
      Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); French hospital; French Day Nursery & Kindergarten Free School; First National Bank; Richmond & West Point Terminal Railway & Warehouse Company; car trust certificates; Charity Building; Charity Organization Society; Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor; veterinary bill; Grande Ligne Mission, Quebec, Canada; Cleveland "Daily Argus;" Standard Oil Company press relations; Cleveland Diet Dispensary and Women's Exchange; Oberlin College; Haven Normal School (Colored); Faith Home Orphanage; personal loan; job applicant; Baptist Church; silver mines in Colorado; General Theological Library; World's Columbian Exposition; income tax; Wake Forest College; Student's Aid Fund; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Illinois Steel Company; F. T. Gates report; University of Chicago.
    - Fasig, W. B. - Fassett & Company, 36.0 pages (Box 14, Folder 107, Reel 12, Frame 0863)
      Cleveland Club; Cleveland Driving Park Company; Northern Ohio Fair Association; Ohio Association of Trotting Horse Breeders; Driving Club of New York; trotting horses; house painters.
    - Faunce, W. H. P., 103.0 pages (Reel 12, Frame 0899, Box 14, Folder 108)
      Pastor, Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; work of church; friendship with John D. Rockefeller; Armitage House Day Nursery and Kindergarten; Brown University; University of Chicago; Baptist Church; student assistance; Woman's Medical College of the New York Infirmary; Woman's Baptist Foreign Missionary Society; poor relief; Mutual Employment Society of New York; personal aid.
    - Faure - Fetzer, 167.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0001, Box 14, Folder 109)
      St. John's Guild Floating Hospital; timber and coal lands in Kentucky; "Dekalb Review;" request for John D. Rockefeller photograph; personal loans; German Baptist Seminary; Baptist Church; personal friend; personal aid; religious interests; job applicants; Federal Club; Northern Pacific Railroad Company; John D. Rockefeller Western trip; Children's Home; gold mines in Idaho; oil wells; Home for Young Women; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); coal mines in Indiana; New York, Lake Erie & Western Railroad Company; revocation of railroad passes; Cleveland Observatory; College of Elocution; Cook Academy; Worker's Mission in Sheffield, England; house servant; attorney; Hamburg, Germany, Baptist missionary.
    - Fiddis - Flack, 105.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0168, Box 14, Folder 110)
      Job applicant; sheriff's jury; New York Free circulating Library; fund for Mrs. James A. Garfield; real estate; Industrial University; manual training school; F. T. Gates report; oak furniture; Baptist Church; Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; Turn Verein; Buchtel College; Canadian Pacific Railway passes for John D. Rockefeller and family; Cumberland Female College; Sweden missionary; Armitage House; University of Chicago; books for sale; personal aid; Women's Christian Association; Eliza Jennings Home for Incurables; the Retreat (shelter for fallen women); Alfred Bierstadt paintings; Garfield Memorial University; Five Points House of Industry for Homeless Children.
    - Flagg, C. D. - Flagg, J. H., 33.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0273, Box 14, Folder 111)
      New York Central Sleeping Car Company; Wagner Palace Car Company; travel arrangements; attorney; U. S. Congress Henley Resolution to Investigate Union Pacific Railroad Company.
    - Flagler, H. M., 39.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0306, Box 15, Folder 112)
      Standard Oil Trust executive; Standard Oil Company employee relations; meeting notices; Central Trust Company; purchase of crude oil; real estate; Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); Charity Organization Society; personal matters; John D. Rockefeller railroad passes; Dwight L. Moody's school; Union Oil Company; Jacksonville, St. Augustine & Halifax River Railway Company; Baptist Church.
    - Fleming - Foster, J. B., 157.0 pages (Box 15, Folder 113, Reel 13, Frame 0345)
      Presbyterian Church; personal aid; John D. Rockefeller physician; job applicant; Methodist Episcopal Church; Percheron horses; New York Ophthalmic Hospital; New York Homeopathic Medical College and Hospital; real estate; Vassar College; adding machine invention; report on petroleum for the state of Pennsylvania; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; Baptist Church; business loan; Alabama High School (Baptist); student assistance; artist; Lake View Cemetery Association; banker and broker; trotting horses; De Land University; John D. Rockefeller relative; Episcopal Church; Baptist Home; University of Chicago newspaper; F. T. Gates report; John D. Rockefeller portrait sittings; temperance work; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Murphy meetings.
    - Foster, J. Ellen, 1883-1889; 112.0 pages (Box 15, Folder 114, Reel 13, Frame 0502)
      Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) Department of Legislation; John D. Rockefeller contributions to temperance work; personal aid; National League for the Suppression of the Liquor Traffic; National Temperance Hospital and Clara Barton Training School for Nurses; Woman's Republican Association; Kansas Humane Society.
    - Foster, J. Ellen, 1880-1893; 57.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0614, Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Foster, James P. - Freeman, J. L., 114.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0671, Box 15, Folder 116)
      Republican League of the United States; Linnaean Society of New York; Baptist Church; Collegiate Institute; job applicant; business loan; Florence, Italy, Ladies International College; Cook Academy; Disciples of Christ Church; New York Skin and Cancer Hospital; Stonega Academy; University of Chicago; personal aid; architect; Bethel Institute; real estate; Congregational Church; Swedish immigrants; German missionary.
    - Freeman, J. F., 38.0 pages (Box 15, Folder 117, Reel 13, Frame 0785)
      Standard Oil Company of New York treasurer; handled some of John D. Rockefeller's investments; stock market activity; financial markets; bonds; loan accounts; accountancy; reports on taxes paid; real estate; Standard Oil Trust shares.
    - Freeman, S. H. - Furnald, F. P., 144.0 pages (Reel 13, Frame 0823, Box 15, Folder 118)
      Baptist Church; personal aid; Commercial National Bank; French Hospital; French Day Nursery and Kindergarten Free School; job applicant; Cemetery monuments; India missionary; Hebrew-Christian Church; Baptist Mission; Standard Oil Company publicity and press relations; lead and zinc ore lands; Standard Oil Company employees; Friend's Home for Children; aluminum and lighting inventions; American Tract Society; Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute; student assistance; Hospital Cottages for Children; Baptist School; International Christian Endeavor Convention; business loan; need for Negro School in Arkansas, Mississippi and Tennessee; car wheel invention; Buckingham Hotel; personal loan; New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor; John D. Rockefeller housekeeper; Baptist missionary to Roman Catholics; Catholic Deaf Mute School; Funk & Wagnalls, temperance; World's Columbia Exhibition; sheriff's jury.
    - J. L. G. (Mrs.) - Garnett, 152.0 pages (Reel 14, Frame 0001, Box 15, Folder 119)
      Personal aid; Baptist Church; U. S. Congress election contribution; Salvation Army; real estate; Woman and Children's hospital; Chicago Atheneum; gas bid; Baptist Mission; Leland University; Wendell Phillips Hall Association; vacation trip for boys; Gas Consumers Association of the State of New York; Cleveland Grays; American College and Education Society (Slavic Department); iron industry; personal loan; Human Society; banking proposal; Episcopal Home for Boys; copper mines in Michigan.
    - Garretson - Gates, E., 80.0 pages (Reel 14, Frame 0153, Box 16, Folder 120)
      Personal aid; Baptist Church; interview request; extradition treaty with Russia; oil lands in Germany; orphanage; real estate; Institute of the Mind.
    - Gates, F. T., 1891-May 1892; 126.0 pages (Box 16, Folder 121, Reel 14, Frame 0233)
      John D. Rockefeller's close adviser; reports on various charities and business proposals; Baptist Church appeals; Brown University; University of Chicago; American Baptist Education Society; Vassar College; Germany missionary; India missionary; American Baptist Home Mission Society; Minnesota steel and iron industry; Gates on John D. Rockefeller payroll after January 1893; E. B. Andrews; International Medical Missionary Society; New York City Baptist Mission Society; Baptist Missionary Convention of the State of New York; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor.
    - Gates, F. T., June-November 1892; 82.0 pages (Box 16, Folder 122, Reel 14, Frame 0359)
    - Gates, F. T., December 1892; 127.0 pages (Box 16, Folder 123, Reel 14, Frame 0441)
    - Gates, F. T., 1893-1894; 100.0 pages (Box 16, Folder 124, Reel 14, Frame 0568)
    - Gatliff - Gilbert, Viola, 141.0 pages (Reel 14, Frame 0668, Box 16, Folder 125)
      Williamsburg, Kentucky, Institute; Japan missionary; job applicants; Moody Bible Institute; Ohio Baptist State Convention; Baptist Church; sheriff's jury; Bible Reader's Home; personal aid; real estate; publisher; history of New York Stock Exchange; book on bible; Ohio National Guard; Point Chautauqua Association; Kalamazoo College; Huron Street Hospital; Columbian Chess Congress; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Industrial Home; Florida Baptist Academy (Negro); Zion's Mission; Women's Baptist Home Mission Society.
    - Gilbert Seminary - Giovannini, 150.0 pages (Reel 14, Frame 0809, Box 16, Folder 126)
      Gilbert Seminary; Armitage House; Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; Ohio Scottish Guard; election appeal; University of Chicago; Baptist Church; Spelman Seminary; F. T. Gates report; American Patriotic League; Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); chimney sweep; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Ohio Baptist State Convention; book for sale; Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute; New York Sabbath Committee; Citizens' Relief Fund Committee; New England Conservatory of Music; music teacher; Madame Giovannini's Select Home School for Young Ladies.
    - Girty - Goodman, Edward, 80.0 pages (Reel 14, Frame 0959, Box 17, Folder 127)
      Standard Oil Company auditor's office; John D. Rockefeller accounting methods; personal aid; reference request; Baptist Church; University of Virginia; job applicant; musician; clipper ship; Glenns Falls Buckboard Company; Fifth Avenue Transportation Company; personal loan; ice delivery; Bethel College of the Mennonite Church of North America; Methodist Episcopal Church; electrician; Pullman's Palace Car Company; John D. Rockefeller travel arrangements; Baptist Theological Union; Chicago Baptist Theological Seminary.
    - Goodman, Fred S., 80.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0001, Box 17, Folder 128)
      Cleveland Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA), general secretary; John D. Rockefeller contributions.
    - Goodsell - Goodspeed, 147.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0081, Box 17, Folder 129)
      Vassar College; student assistance; Chicago Baptist Theological Seminary; John D. Rockefeller contributions.
    - Goodwillie - Grand Army of the Republic, 118.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0228, Box 17, Folder 130)
      Character reference; Baptist Church; Standard Oil Company shipments and prices; benefit show for poor children; Wellesley College; Christopher Columbus Statue; New York Kindergarten Association; Columbian University; Southern Industrial Home for Confederate Veterans and Families; personal aid; job applicant; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); commission brokers; personal loan; sheriff's jury; furnace company; last will of Jay Gould; temperance work; real estate; florist; steamship investment offer; Muskingum College; Church Temperance Society; Scharwenka Conservatory of Music; F. T. Gates report; Grand Army of the Republic benefit events.
    - Granger - Greene, 125.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0346, Box 17, Folder 131)
      Baptist Church Ladies Society; Baptist Church; bookseller; character reference; Mayor of New York City; Committee for International Exposition of 1892; Johnstown flood sufferers; American Committee for Relief of Famine in Ireland; Riverside Improvement Commission; personal aid; real estate; Ulysses S. Grant's birthday anniversary; fire extinguishers; lumber; Cribside Committee of the Babies Hospital; student assistance; Baptist Mission; Lake County Bank; Christopher Columbus Monument Fair; attorneys; opera glasses; business proposal; Baptist Missionary Society of England; Peddie Institute; Congregational Church.
    - Greensted - Grier, 71.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0471, Box 17, Folder 132)
      Baptist Church; Driving Club of New York; job applicant; Howard University; personal aid; student assistance; Fifth Avenue Baptist Church.
    - Griffin, Albert, 53.0 pages (Box 17, Folder 133, Reel 15, Frame 0542)
      Anti-Saloon Republican National Committee, chairman; temperance work; National Temperance Lecture Bureau.
    - Griffin, E. M. - Gross, 97.0 pages (Box 17, Folder 134, Reel 15, Frame 0595)
      Baptist Church; life insurance; North Granville Seminary; iron bill; mica mines in North Carolina; American Baptist Publication Society; job applicant; swindler; Presbyterian Church; Siberian Exile Petition Association; Equitable Life Assurance Society; Indiana College Company; personal aid; German Baptist Education Society of North America; Rochester Theological Seminary; National Transit Company, president; John D. Rockefeller railroad passes; European trip; Inman & International Steamship Company; social matters; importer.
    - Grossmayer - Gwin, 62.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 135, Reel 15, Frame 0692)
      Hebrew Reformed Congregation; German Evangelical Protestant Church; personal matters; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) foreign work; Baptist Church; photograph request; Lutheran Mission; personal aid; real estate; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Baptist Orphanage; job applicant; horse for sale.
    - Haaff - Hamlen, 176.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 136, Reel 15, Folder 0754)
      Chicago Baptist Theological Seminary; St. Paul German Insurance Company; personal matters; Johnstown flood sufferers; Jerry McAuley Mission; Grand Army of the Republic Mission; F. T. Gates report; job applicant; Baptist Church; Howard Mission; personal aid; Persian & East India Company rugs and carpets; Hahnemann Hospital; American Baptist Home Mission Society; Southwest Baptist College; attorney; bankers; Citizens Bank of Lost Angeles, California; death of J. W. Hale; business proposal; Vermont Marble Company; Woman's Temperance Publication Association; New York "Tribune;" real estate; Christian Retreat; New York Tax Reform Association; publisher and art importer; Swedish Baptist Church; Home Relief Association; "Christian at Work" newspaper; Society for the Prevention of Crime; Sheffield Farm; money collectors; Soldiers Monument; Rochester City Hospital; East Nashville College (School for young Ladies); Baptist Female College; personal loan.
    - Haaff - Hamlen, 128.0 pages (Reel 15, Frame 0930, Box 18, Folder 137)
      Job applicant; Southwest Baptist College; Baptist Church; Richmond Female Institute; National Switch & Signal Company; "The Press;" Driving Club of New York; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); University of Chicago; Episcopal Church; Richmond Institute; Hampton Normal & Agricultural Institute; Baptist mission; Merchants National Bank; Mercantile National Bank; Huron Street Hospital; D. B. Bedell & Company china and glass importers; grapevines and orange groves in California; Hanna, Chapin & Company refiners and dealers in petroleum; Charity Organization Society; Standard Oil Trust shares; M. A. Hanna & Company; coal, iron ore, and pig iron; Republican Party election campaigns.
    - Hansell, George H., 127.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 138, Reel 16, Frame 0001)
      Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, treasurer; reports on various charities; New York Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor; Baptist City Mission; Baptist Church.
    - Hanson - Harper, W. R., 159.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 139, Reel 16, Frame 0128)
      Norway missionary; American Baptist Foreign Missionary Association; Russian Relief Committee; job applicant; university of Chicago; American Fine Arts Society; Baptist Church; Nataorium; New York Ladies' Guide and Chaperon Bureau; oil industry business proposal; social matters; real estate; Standard Oil Company executive; India missionary; personal aid; National Bichloride of Gold Company treatment for drunkenness; magazine article on horses; John D. Rockefeller support of Hebrew language schools; Institute of Hebrew; Summer Schools of Hebrew; Correspondence School of Hebrew; Yale University; American Institute of Sacred Literature; theological seminaries; university of Chicago; American Baptist Education Society; Chatauqua Baptist Union; F. T. Gates reports; Columbia college Torrey Botanical Club; Botanical Garden and Museum and Arboretum in Bronx Park.
    - Harrington - Hart, 81.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 140, Reel 16, Frame 0287)
      Copper mines; Baptist Church; Central High School reunion; personal aid; Home for Children of Missionaries; real estate in Minnesota; books for sale; stock market investments; letter of introduction; paint manufacturer; job applicant; Brooks Academy; Military Order of the Loyal Legion; election contribution to Harrison Boys in Blue (Benjamin Harrison U. S. presidential campaign); University of Pennsylvania; Methodist Episcopal Church; oil lands; business opportunity in Georgia.
    - Hartley, Richard, 1885-1891; 128.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 141, Reel 16, Frame 0368)
      Hope Baptist Church; New York Baptist City Mission; John D. Rockefeller gifts to churches; F. T. Gates reports.
    - Hartley, Richard, 1892-1894; 60.0 pages (Box 18, Folder 142, Reel 16, Frame 0496)
    - Hartman - Haydn, 171.0 pages (Box 19, Folder 143, Reel 16, Frame 0556)
      Newspaper article request; job applicant; real estate; European guide; John D. Rockefeller travel arrangements; Baptist Church; American Baptist Missionary Union; Episcopal Church; school in Turkey; Cleveland Philharmonic Orchestra; stamp dealer; University of the City of New York; Cleveland Chamber of Commerce; personal aid; school for girls; inquiry about John D. Rockefeller relative; Vassar College Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); Howard Mission and Home for Little Wanderers; Lake View Cemetery; Baptist Orphanage of Virginia; Colored Baptist Church; Union League Club; art for sale; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; interview request; Florence, Alabama, Baptist Church; Western Reserve University; Lake Erie Female Seminary.
    - Hayes - Haywood, 128.0 pages (Reel 16, Frame 0727, Box 19, Folder 144)
      Woman's Benevolent Association; business proposal; skylight; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU) reading rooms; personal loan; insurance agent; Townsend Library; Ohio National Guard; Art Loan Exhibition; Turkey missionary; Baptist Church; Methodist Episcopal Church; support for John D. Rockefeller business policies; personal aid; Cook Academy; optician; Shurtleff College.
    - Hazelhuhn, J. C., 143.0 pages (Reel 16, Frame 0855, Box 19, Folder 145)
      German Baptist Church in Cleveland, Ohio; John D. Rockefeller contributions; John D. Rockefeller gifts to other German Baptist churches through Hazelhuhn; Germany missionary; German Baptist Publication Society; F. T. Gates report.
    - Healy - Herrick, C., 159.0 pages (Reel 17, Frame 0001, Box 19, Folder 146)
      The Health Life gymnastics system; Vassar College alumnae; Baptist Church; Charity Organization Society; Missouri, Kansas & Texas Railway Company pass; personal aid; personal loan; Women' s Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Pratt Institute; Institute of Hebrew; Peary Relief Committee expedition to Arctic; Lutheran missionary; Germany Baptist Publication Society; real estate; Reformed Church; American Baptist Home Mission Society; F. T. Gates report; University of chicago; ice plant securities; Christmas gift for mailman; deposition regarding oil industry; Carson and Newman College; copper and silver mines in Montana; Lutheran Church; kerosene lamp and oil stove inventions; Provident Dispensary for Working Women and Girls; German Baptist English Academy in the West; General Missionary Society of German Baptist Churches; lace curtains; Lima Normal College; job applicant; Herald Printing company; coal merchants; furniture; business loan; Western Reserve Academy; temperance work; local option prohibition laws.
    - Herrick, G. E. - Heye, 106.0 pages (Reel 17, Frame 0160, Box 19, Folder 147)
      Cleveland Bethel; political contributions; Harrison Boys in Blue (Benjamin Harrison U. S. presidential campaign); National Republican Committee; Ohio Sunday Law; Cleveland Philharmonic Orchestra; job applicants; Hebrew Educational Fair; Ladies' Fuel & Aid Society; fine art dealer; Hiram College; Orchestra at German-American School; Saginaw Bay Company; personal aid; Baptist Church; Chicago Baptist Theological Union; North-Western Baptist Educational Society; University of Chicago; F. T. Gates report; Standard Oil Company of Indiana; cellos for sale; North German Lloyd Steamship Company; John D. Rockefeller European trip.
    - Hibbard - Higgins, Hamilton, 127.0 pages (Reel 17, Frame 0266, Box 19, Folder 148)
      Academy at Rockefeller, Illinois; oil lands; International Sabbath Association; work among the foreign-born; American Sabbath Union; American Railway Literary Union and Pure Literature Bureau; Woman's Home Missionary Union; temperance newspaper; Baptist Church; personal aid; Clinton College; Standard Oil Trust shares; missionary to Kiowa Indians; job applicant; trotting horses; character reference.
    - Higgins, Henry E. - Hitchon, 107.0 pages (Box 19, Folder 149, Reel 17, Frame 0393)